[Music]
[音乐]
good afternoon everyone thanks for
大家下午好，谢谢
coming to this session on rest and graph
参加本次会议的休息和图表
QL and Java and spring and I think he's
QL，Java和Spring，我认为他是
already done an introduction so I don't
已经做了介绍，所以我不
need to do anything as I say that I'm
我需要做任何事情，因为我说我
also a Java champion among other things
也是Java冠军
the last one is my favorite the pearl
最后一颗是我最喜欢的珍珠
recovery group how many people still
恢复组还有多少人
code in Perl today anybody okay so a few
今天在Perl中编写代码的人还可以
people yeah we're gonna meet at 6:30 for
是的，我们要在6:30见面
beers in the Pro recovery group
专业恢复组中的啤酒
downstairs so anyways one thing quick I
楼下所以反正一件事我
want to say is that if you're not
想说的是，如果你不
familiar with what IBM does in the
熟悉IBM在
spring world we do lots and lots of
春季世界，我们做了很多
different things spring works really
春天真的起作用了
well on IBM cloud and we have an amazing
在IBM Cloud上很好，我们有一个了不起的
runtime called open j9 which is a drop
称为open j9的运行时
in substitution for adopt open JDK and
代替采用开放式JDK和
the hotspot VM so they especially open
热点VM，因此它们特别开放
j9 it uses less memory and starts up
j9它使用较少的内存并启动
faster and lots and lots of other stuff
更快，还有很多其他的东西
but come by the IBM booth get a free
但是在IBM展位前来免费
t-shirt like this and come hang out with
像这样的T恤，可以和他们一起出去玩
us and obviously we're going to have
我们，显然我们将拥有
beverages sponsored by IBM later today
IBM今天晚些时候赞助的饮料
so before I get started I just want to
所以在我开始之前，我只想
take a quick survey how many people are
快速调查有多少人
currently using graph QL ok so a few
当前使用图QL好的，所以一些
people how many people are using it with
人们有多少人正在使用它
Java on the back end graph QL server ok
后端图QL服务器上的Java正常
now what I want to do is do a quick
现在我要做的是快速
introduction to graph QL and then look
图QL的介绍，然后看看
at an implementation of graph QL written
在图QL的实现中编写
with two different libraries that help
有两个不同的库可以提供帮助
you build out a graph QL solution on on
您建立了一个图QL解决方案
Java on the server side so let's talk
服务器端的Java，让我们谈谈
about graph QL a little bit the first
关于图QL首先
thing about graph QL is that it is
关于图QL的事情是
actually a query language right that's
实际上是一种查询语言权利
what graph QL stands for graph query
QL代表什么图形查询
language so it's very similar to how we
语言，这与我们的方式非常相似
do programming in Java world where when
在Java世界中进行编程
we're building inheritance model using
我们正在使用建立继承模型
Java classes we're essentially building
我们本质上正在构建的Java类
out an object graph right we sometimes
出一个对象图，有时候我们
call it a tree but it is actually a
称它为树，但实际上是
graph when you're doing object-oriented
面向对象时的图形
programming so graph QL actually can
进行编程，因此图QL实际上可以
mirror the way that we build
反映我们的建设方式
applications with domain driven design
具有域驱动设计的应用程序
and go into the domain driven
并进入域驱动
development quite well because it Matt
发展很好，因为它是马特
is up to the way that we already build
取决于我们已经建立的方式
applications in the java world using o
使用o的Java世界中的应用程序
design okay
设计还可以
now you might be thinking well we have
现在你可能在想我们有
to learn another language
学习另一种语言
fortunately graph kill is very simple
幸运的是，图杀死非常简单
and straightforward there's not much
直截了当
difference in terms of the way that we
在方式上的差异
as think as object-oriented Java
认为是面向对象的Java
developers already but yes it is a new
开发人员已经是，但是是新的
language and it is a new specification
语言，这是一个新规范
so it takes a little bit of time to
所以要花一点时间
understand some of the nuances around it
了解周围的一些细微差别
and how to build things with it I hope
以及如何用它来构建东西
to do that in the next 47 minutes here
在接下来的47分钟内在此处执行此操作
today okay so the other thing to note is
今天好，所以要注意的另一件事是
that graph qaul is an API query language
该图qaul是一种API查询语言
and the key word there being API okay so
还有关键词，API还可以，所以
the emphasis on graph QL is around
关于图QL的重点是
building api's and as we go through and
建立api，随着我们的经历，
do some demos you'll see hopefully how
做一些演示，您将希望看到如何
that works in terms of going and
就去和
building out graph QL queries and how
建立图QL查询以及如何
they relate to an API that you're
它们与您所使用的API有关
building behind it okay so graph QL was
在它后面建好，所以图QL是
created by Facebook and was open sourced
由Facebook创建并开源
in 2015 and it has been maintained as
在2015年，它一直保持为
part of the essentially a community
本质上是社区的一部分
effort now and it is more than anything
现在付出努力，这比什么都重要
else it's a specification there's not a
否则这是一个规范，没有
implementation or a reference
实施或参考
implementation of graph QL okay so it's
图QL的实现还可以，所以
more specification than an
规格多于
implementation and when we do some demos
实施以及我们进行一些演示时
and code here in a few minutes what
并在几分钟内在这里编码
we're going to see is implementations of
我们将看到的是
the graphical specification on the
上的图形规范
server side because that's one thing
服务器端，因为那是一回事
important to note that it is actually a
重要的是要注意，它实际上是一个
spec and not an implementation so how
规范，而不是实现，如何
many people watch Silicon Valley in here
很多人在这里看硅谷
is that okay so good I wasn't sure if it
那样好吗，我不确定是否
was just us in America who watch it but
只是我们在美国观看
anyways this is a scene from Silicon
无论如何，这是硅的一幕
Valley so you might be thinking we just
山谷，所以您可能会认为我们只是
rewrote all of our API Zoar endpoints or
重写了我们所有的API Zoar端点，或者
whatever using rest and now I'm up here
无论使用休息，现在我在这里
telling you that you should look at
告诉你应该看
something like graph QL right and maybe
像图QL这样的东西，也许
you're feeling like the guys in this
你感觉就像这个家伙
picture we should just burn it all down
图片，我们应该把它全部烧掉
and why do we bother alright so yes you
为什么我们要打扰好了，是的，你
may have rewritten everything in rest or
可能已经重写了所有静止的内容，或者
maybe you're in the process of moving
也许你正在搬家
over to a more restful based API in
转到基于更宁静的API
architecture
建筑
but the nice thing about graph QL is
但是关于图QL的好处是
that it is not a pure replacement for
它不是纯粹的替代品
rest the way that I like to think about
休息我喜欢的思考方式
it is that graph QL is just another tool
QL图只是另一个工具
in your tool belt for building
在您的工具带中进行建造
applications so you don't have to throw
应用程序，因此您不必抛出
away everything that you've written and
丢掉你写的所有东西，
rest you can happily coexist with rest
休息，你可以快乐地与休息共存
and with graph QL on the same server or
并在同一服务器上使用图QL或
in the same architecture you can use
在相同的架构中，您可以使用
both if you want which is really nice
如果你想两者都很好
okay we'll get into that a little bit as
好吧，我们将进入
well in a few minutes and one of the
几分钟之内就可以完成
things you can actually do is that if
你实际上可以做的是
you already have restful api is
您已经有一个宁静的api是
especially if you have a restful
尤其是如果您休息
distributed api that's in multiple
多个分布式API
different endpoints of multiple
多个端点
different servers or services or however
不同的服务器或服务
you've designed your architecture you
您已经设计了架构，
can actually wrap your underlying
实际上可以包装您的基础
restful api with graph QL on top and
带有图QL的Restful API
this is actually a very powerful
这实际上是非常强大的
extraction because you can have multiple
提取，因为您可以有多个
teams that are building things maybe
正在构建事物的团队
they already have built things in brest
他们已经在布雷斯特建造了东西
they have api's exposed and rest you can
他们的api已暴露，您可以休息
actually go and just wrap them and
实际去包装它们
create like a meta api on top of
像元api一样创建
existing api's so that your front-end
现有的api，以便您的前端
applications or your mobile applications
应用程序或您的移动应用程序
have a single unified entry point into
有一个统一的入口
all these different disparate api's and
所有这些不同的api和
data sources and again we'll get into
数据源，我们将再次探讨
that in a few minutes as well all right
几分钟后就可以了
so as mentioned already we can have any
所以如上所述，我们可以有任何
data sources underneath and in fact with
数据源在下面，实际上是
graph QL because it's just a
图QL，因为它只是一个
specification for the front-end or from
前端或从
the front to the back end it doesn't
前端到后端不是
even have to be a data source it doesn't
甚至不必成为一个数据源
have to be a database in the back you
必须是你背后的数据库
can have something else running in the
可以在其中运行其他内容
background and wrap that with a graph
背景并用图形包装
cue all API which is actually super
提示所有实际上超级的API
powerful
强大
okay so we'll look at that as well in a
好吧，我们也将在
minute now one thing that's different
分钟，一件事是不同的
about graph QL compared to restful
关于图QL与宁静
endpoints is that it is a single
端点是一个单一的
endpoint so when you set up a graph QL
端点，所以当您设置图形QL时
instance it will only go to one place
实例只会去一个地方
all right slash graphic you all or
可以全部使用斜线图形或
whatever you want to call it and the
随便你怎么称呼它
other interesting thing about graphic
关于图形的其他有趣的事情
you all compared to rest is that it is
你们所有人与休息相比，它是
schema based right we'll have a look at
基于模式的权利，我们来看一下
a graph kill scheme in a minute when we
我们在一分钟内完成图杀死计划
go and explore what it actually looks
去探索它的实际外观
like but these are the two key
就像，但这是两个关键
differences and we'll talk about more
差异，我们将讨论更多
but the two key differences
但是两个主要区别
between graph QL and standard rest is
在图QL和标准休止点之间是
that there's a single endpoint instead
而是有一个端点
of multiple endpoints you know when
您知道何时的多个端点
you're building out a restful endpoint
您正在建立一个宁静的终点
you may have a slash users endpoint and
您可能有一个斜线用户端点，并且
you may have slash shopping cart or
您可能有大幅削减购物车或
slash items or whatever so you have
削减项目或其他
different endpoints with graph QL you
图QL的不同端点
only have one endpoint and you send a
只有一个端点，您发送一个
query in to get the exact data that you
查询以获取您的确切数据
need and there is a schema behind it so
需要，背后有一个架构，所以
instead of being something that you just
而不是只是你
construct on the fly and you say well
快速构建，你说的很好
this is our users endpoint and we have
这是我们的用户端点，我们有
the four verbs HTTP verbs to get and
要获取的四个动词HTTP动词和
post and put et cetera graph QL can take
QL可以采取的放置等条件图
either get or post but single endpoint
获取或发布，但单个端点
and we pass it a query to see what it
我们向它传递查询以查看它是什么
looks like and we're going to do that
看起来像，我们将这样做
now okay it's time for a quick demo and
现在好了，是时候进行快速演示了
you know how demos work
你知道演示如何工作
so hopefully this works well all right
所以希望这一切正常
so let's have a quick look at a few
让我们快速浏览一下
queries here and hopefully that's big
在这里查询，希望很大
enough let's double check yeah it should
足够让我们仔细检查是的
be fine all right so what I have here
很好，所以我在这里
first we start with query and we say all
首先我们从查询开始，然后说全部
starships get me the starships
飞船让我飞船
underneath and the name in the model and
下面和模型中的名称以及
you can see that's printed here but
你可以看到印在这里，但是
let's go and actually amount to that and
我们走吧，实际上等于
let's see what we can do let's say what
让我们看看我们能做什么让我们说什么
class of starship is that and let's go
星际飞船的一类就是，让我们开始吧
run this and you can see that now we get
运行它，您可以看到现在我们得到了
the starship classes Corvette and this
星舰级的护卫舰和这个
is a destroyer of course this is from
是驱逐舰，当然这是
Star Wars but let's see what other data
星球大战，但让我们看看还有哪些其他数据
points we can add here ok and you can
点，我们可以在这里添加好，你可以
see as I'm working through this this is
看到我正在为此工作，这是
what's called graphical or graph eql
所谓的图形或图形方程式
which is a browser for an underlying
这是底层浏览器
graph QL endpoint ok so we could say
图QL端点确定，所以我们可以说
let's see how big the different types of
让我们看看不同类型的
starships are so you can see these are
星舰是，所以你可以看到这些是
the length of course a Star Destroyer is
当然，“星际驱逐舰”的长度是
much bigger than ACR 90 Corvette now
现在比ACR 90 Corvette大得多
let's actually see how we can go look at
让我们看看如何去看
this a little bit more detail so what we
这一点更多的细节，所以我们
can actually do is because graph QL
实际能做的是因为图QL
produces a schema we can actually go
产生一个我们可以实际去的模式
look at the schema and if you have a
查看模式，如果有
developer who's not on your back-end
不在后端的开发人员
team where the graph QL is actually
图QL实际上所在的团队
produced your front-end developer
生产了您的前端开发人员
whether mobile or web developer can
移动或网络开发人员可以
actually come here into this graphical
实际来到这里这个图形
Explorer for your graph QL endpoint and
图QL端点的资源管理器和
have a look at actually what all is
看看实际上是什么
exposed
裸露
through your graph QL API right so you
通过您的图QL API，这样您
can see that in this specific
可以看到在这个具体
demonstration API we've so far been
到目前为止，我们已经使用了演示API
looking at starships so if I go down to
看着飞船，所以如果我去
starships here's the starship relation
星际飞船这是星际飞船的关系
and I can click into here and we can go
我可以点击这里，我们可以去
look at what are the different types of
看看有哪些不同类型的
things under that all right so we have
一切都好，所以我们有
starships and all of the schema that is
星际飞船和所有的架构
associated associated with that specific
与那个特定的关联
type of starship alright so we can see
好吧，所以我们可以看到
here's a description of all the
这是所有的描述
different fields which are made
制成的不同领域
available to us so we have name model
可供我们使用，所以我们有名称模型
class who's the manufacturer let's go
谁是制造商，我们走吧
see who makes the manufacturers right
看看谁使制造商正确
and again because we have a predefined
再次因为我们有一个预定义
schema on this we have this tool which
关于这个模式，我们有这个工具
allows us to go and browse and inspect
允许我们去浏览和检查
and look at this specific graph QL
并查看这个特定的图QL
endpoint that we have so we can come
我们拥有的终点，因此我们可以来
into here and we can say who are the
进入这里，我们可以说谁是
different manufacturers of that let's
那不同的制造商
get rid of this for now right now if we
如果我们现在就暂时摆脱这个
go run this you'll see that we can go
去运行这个，你会看到我们可以去
and see that these are the different
并看到这些是不同的
types of people who make that Star Wars
进行《星球大战》的人的类型
starship right but let's go back here
星河吧，但让我们回到这里
real quick and we should be able to also
很快，我们应该也可以
see what films that specific starship
看看那部特定的飞船电影
appeared in so again we're in we're just
出现了，所以我们再次进入
browsing the graph QL schema here using
在此处浏览图QL模式
this tool called graphic QL or graphical
此工具称为图形QL或图形
and we can see all the different things
我们可以看到所有不同的东西
which are contained in it but if we
其中包含但如果我们
scroll down a little bit we can also see
向下滚动一点我们也可以看到
that there's this something called film
有所谓的电影
connection so now if I go into film
连接，所以现在如果我去看电影
connection we can see that there's
连接，我们可以看到
basically different types of films that
基本上不同类型的电影
are associated with each starship so I
与每个飞船相关，所以我
can come into here and I'm not gonna try
可以进入这里，我不会尝试
to type this all out right now alright
马上输入所有内容
so I'm gonna go and run this specific
所以我要去运行这个特定的
thing it's the same as before let's
事情跟以前一样让我们
query all the starships let's get the
查询所有的星际飞船，让我们
name and model called philip connect to
名称和型号称为philip connect to
many relationship in this case remember
在这种情况下有很多关系记得
graph QL is a schema it's not it's
图QL是一个架构，不是
different than sequel it's not the same
与续集不同这是不一样的
thing as SQL or sequel it's more of a a
作为SQL或续集的东西更多
graph based schema rather than a
基于图的模式而不是
relational schema but in this case we
关系模式，但在这种情况下，我们
have a relationship from starship in two
有两个来自星际飞船的关系
films right here so let's go run this
电影就在这里，让我们去运行这个
and we'll see that the
我们会看到
90 Corvette appeared the first movie it
90 Corvette出现了第一部电影
appeared in was a new hope and then the
出现是一个新的希望，然后
Star Destroyer also appeared in a new
星际驱逐舰也出现在新的
hope and let's scroll down to see if we
希望，让我们向下滚动以查看是否
can find a different one right so the
可以找到另一种权利，所以
imperial shuttle first appeared in the
皇家航天飞机首先出现在
Empire Strikes Back now the way it was
帝国反击
only the way I was able to get the first
只有我能够获得第一个的方式
one is I used an attribute here called
一个是我在这里使用了一个称为
first and said give me the first film
首先说给我第一部电影
that that starship appeared in so I can
那个飞船出现了，所以我可以
put two here and go run that and now
在这里放两个，然后立即运行
we'll see that for example the Star
我们将看到例如星
Destroyer appears in a new hope and also
驱逐舰出现了新的希望
in the Empire Strikes Back now if I get
在《帝国反击战》中
rid of this all together
一起摆脱这一切
you can probably guess what's going to
你可能会猜到会发生什么
happen right it'll show me all the films
发生吧，它将带我看所有电影
that that specific starship appeared in
那个特定的飞船出现在
okay so what we're doing is we're just
好吧，我们要做的就是
very simply using the graph QL query
非常简单地使用图QL查询
language exploring what we can do with
探索我们可以做什么的语言
the graph QL endpoint alright so let's
图QL端点好了，让我们
do a couple of extra ones here so we did
在这里多做几个，所以我们做了
this first one with the film connection
第一个与电影的联系
we can also go get the count so I can
我们也可以去计数，以便我可以
say query all starships count and I'm
说查询所有的飞船计数，我是
gonna go run that and you can see that
去跑那个，你可以看到
doesn't work huh why doesn't that work
没用吧，那为什么没用
it says in the message that can occur if
它说，如果
you'll count on starship do you mean
你会指望星际飞船
total connection um so let's go put that
总连接数，所以让我们去
in and actually I didn't need to go and
进入，实际上我不需要去
look at the error message I could have
看我可能有的错误信息
just come into here and when I hit
刚到这里，当我打
control space it shows me all of the
控制空间，它向我展示了所有
attributes or the fields that I have
属性或我拥有的字段
access to which is really nice
访问哪个真的很好
so if you have a new developer who's
因此，如果您有一个新的开发人员
come onto your project into your company
进入您的项目进入公司
and they're the front-end developer or
他们是前端开发人员，或者
even if they're a back-end developer you
即使他们是后端开发人员
can just say disco browse the graph QL
可以说迪斯科浏览图形QL
endpoint to learn all the different
端点学习所有不同
things we expose in some way this can
我们可以以某种方式公开的东西
also serve as documentation how many
也可以作为文档
people love writing documentation in
人们喜欢在其中编写文档
here anybody okay there must be this
这里任何人都一定有这个
room must be full of developers because
房间里必须满是开发商，因为
me as a developer I hate writing
我是一个我讨厌写的开发人员
documentation but you have to do it
文档，但您必须这样做
right but this is great because from the
是的，但这很好，因为从
schema we can get this documentation
模式，我们可以获取此文档
essentially for free
本质上是免费的
okay anyways so let's see and go run
好的，无论如何，让我们看看并开始跑步
this and this database has a total of 37
这个，这个数据库共有37个
starships inside of it alright so the
里面的星舰好吧
other thing we can do which is
我们可以做的另一件事是
interesting is that we can go and get
有趣的是，我们可以去得到
something from one collection the
来自一个集合的东西
starships collection
星际飞船系列
and in the same call also get something
在同一个电话中也得到了一些东西
that's totally unrelated
那是完全无关的
so the different species in the Star
所以星中不同的物种
Wars world has nothing to do with the
战争世界与
different starships right they're
他们是不同的飞船
totally different so I can go and run
完全不同，所以我可以去跑步
this and at the top I'll get all my
这个，在顶部，我将全力以赴
starships so let's just collapse all the
星际飞船，让我们将所有
starships and then right underneath it
星际飞船，然后在它下面
you'll see that I have a list of all the
您会看到我有所有列表
species in the Star Wars universe so I'm
星球大战宇宙中的物种，所以我
basically going and fetching two
基本上去取两个
collections in the same database or in
同一数据库或同一数据库中的集合
the same graph qo call right and I'll
相同的图qo调用权，我将
tell you about why this is important in
告诉你为什么这很重要
a few minutes but essentially I'm able
几分钟，但基本上我可以
to go get two different unrelated
去得到两个不同的无关
collections which are inside of I schema
I模式内部的集合
in the same API call okay we already
在相同的API调用中，好的，我们已经
looked at how we can do collections
看了我们如何做收藏
traversal from starships into films
从飞船到电影的穿越
right this is a one-to-many relationship
对，这是一对多关系
of course or maybe a many-to-many
当然，也许是多对多
relationship because probably different
关系，因为可能不同
starships appeared in different films
星际飞船出现在不同的电影中
and vice versa
反之亦然
alright so the other thing we can do is
好吧，所以我们可以做的另一件事是
when we're constructing this alright so
当我们构建这个好吧
we're just the queries just a string
我们只是查询只是一个字符串
that we're doing so say we're using a
就是说我们正在使用
JavaScript front-end how many people
JavaScript前端有多少人
build front-end and JavaScript as well
建立前端和JavaScript
just out of curiosity
出于好奇
so for a number of people so when we're
所以对于很多人来说，当我们
building this in JavaScript how do we do
在JavaScript中构建该代码
this there are some libraries that help
这有一些帮助的图书馆
you build a graph QL queries in
您在建立图QL查询
JavaScript and similarly for iOS and
JavaScript，以及类似的iOS和
Android but we don't want to do like
Android，但我们不想这么做
string concatenation and string
字符串连接和字符串
construction when we want to reuse a
当我们想重用一个
query over and over again so you might
一遍又一遍地查询，所以您可能
say inside of my application I want to
在我的应用程序内部说
go and get the starship multiple times
去多次获得星舰
right but I want to get different ones
是的，但我想换一个
and we don't want to come in here and do
而且我们不想进来做
string concatenation or for example let
字符串连接或例如让
me go find the right one I have it here
我去找合适的，我在这里
somewhere or maybe I don't right so I
某个地方，或者我不正确，所以我
may not want to go and actually get and
可能不想去实际上得到
hard-code the actual name of the
硬编码实际名称
starship inside of my application of
我的应用中的星际飞船
course I can't find it I've written in
当然我找不到我写的
earlier there it is oh all right
早些时候哦，好吧
anyways so what we can do is we can use
无论如何，所以我们可以做的就是可以使用
essentially query parameters like we
本质上查询像我们这样的参数
have in this example so what we do is
在这个例子中，所以我们要做的是
when we construct graph QL on the client
当我们在客户端上构造图QL时
we can say here my query variables I'm
我们可以在这里说我的查询变量
going to call it starship ID with this
用这个来称它为星际ID
specific ID and then in my graph QL
具体ID，然后在我的图形QL中
query I
查询我
say dollar starship ID again that's this
再说一遍美元星际身份证就是这样
thing right here right and it's we give
事情就在这里，这是我们给的
it a type of ID exclamation point so
它是一种ID感叹号
this is the other thing about graph QL
这是关于图QL的另一件事
which is interesting is that not only do
有趣的是，不仅
we define the structure of our data or
我们定义数据的结构或
of our schema we also put in the
在我们的架构中，我们还将
specific type that each field and each
每个字段和每个字段的特定类型
data element is so in this case we're
数据元素是这样，在这种情况下
saying that this I the starship ID is of
说这是我的飞船ID
type ID and then we're able to go and
输入ID，然后我们就可以
use that to go and fetch a specific
用它去获取一个特定的
starship like so okay so we looked at
像这样的星际飞船，所以我们看着
how to traverse relationships how to use
如何遍历关系如何使用
query parameters how to use pagination
查询参数如何使用分页
and modifiers like first so that we can
和第一个修饰符，这样我们就可以
just get a page of data if we want and
如果需要的话，只获取一页数据
other things like that all right
像这样的其他事情
oops all right so let's go back to here
糟糕，让我们回到这里
not now
现在不要
all right so let's make sure we covered
好吧，让我们确保我们覆盖了
everything we talked about how we can
我们谈论过的一切
traverse a relationship like so we
遍历像这样的关系
talked about how we can get a count and
谈到我们如何获得计数
how we can do a query this is what I was
我们怎么做查询，这就是我
looking for earlier right so we don't
寻找更早的权利，所以我们不
want to hard-code the ID like we have
想要像我们一样对ID进行硬编码
here we'd rather use a query variable so
这里我们宁愿使用查询变量
that we can reuse the same string and go
我们可以重复使用相同的字符串
and get a result out of it all right and
并从中得到结果，
then we did this as well how do we do
然后我们也这样做了
use query variables now if you noticed
如果您发现现在使用查询变量
when we were inside of our graph QL
当我们进入图QL时
queries let's go back to this one right
查询让我们回到这一权利
here okay let's find a simple one right
好的，让我们找到一个简单的权利
so like this or if we look at this you
像这样或如果我们看着这个你
can see that I had to type everything
可以看到我必须键入所有内容
out let's say structure class
我们说一下结构类
manufacturers oops
制造商哎呀
and and I keep hitting the wrong button
而且我一直按错了按钮
for some reason okay sorry
出于某种原因，对不起
costing credits and maybe we'll do the
花费信用额，也许我们会做
length and etc etc right but in graph QL
长度等等等，但是在图QL中
you do have to go and type every single
你必须去打字每一个
field that you want you can't just say
您想要的字段，您不能只说
start there's no wild-card parameter in
开始没有通配符参数
graph QL right so like in rest you can
对QL进行图形绘制，这样就可以休息了
just say go get me all the user info and
只是说去给我所有的用户信息，
you get all the user info right how can
您正确获得所有用户信息
you get every field in an object the
您得到对象中的每个字段
short answer is that in graft
简而言之，就是嫁接
you cannot you have to be explicit about
你可以不必明确
which specific fields you want from a
您要从哪个特定字段
specific object now it's actually a
具体对象，现在实际上是
deliberate thing that there's a wild
故意有野外的事情
card to get everything you have to
卡获得所需的一切
specify every field that you want in a
在一个字段中指定所需的每个字段
graph QL object that is in the schema
模式中的图形QL对象
that is actually by design and not on
这实际上是设计使然，而不是
purpose so at this point you're probably
目的，所以此时您可能
thinking well if we're going and getting
如果我们要去并得到
having to type every field every time we
每次我们都要输入每个字段
want to go get it is this a good thing
想去得到它是一件好事
or is it an anti-pattern or is it just
还是反模式还是仅仅是
bad or he's just ready to leave and just
不好，或者他只是准备离开而已
stay on rest well the reason why and
保持良好休息的原因
they shut the lights off can you still
他们关灯了你还能吗
see me in the dark is that okay all
在黑暗中看到我，好吗
right so I don't want to stand there the
对，所以我不想站在那儿
whole time all right so this is actually
一直没事，所以这实际上是
a good thing because there are a couple
好东西，因为有一对
of things that it enforces number one
它强制执行第一件事
you only get what you asked for
你只会得到你想要的
so you don't get everything say that you
所以你不会得到一切都说你
have a really big object that you're
有一个很大的东西，你
exposing to your restful endpoint you
暴露于宁静的端点
don't go and get everything all right
不要去让一切都好
and that's actually a good thing you can
这实际上是一件好事
the other thing with graph QL as you saw
如您所见，还有图QL的另一件事
previously is that I can go get things
以前是我可以去拿东西
from two unrelated objects in the same
来自同一个中两个不相关的对象
call
呼叫
sometimes when you're building out the
有时候，当您建造
front end for a an application and you
应用程序的前端，您
need two different things from two
需要两个不同的东西
different places and you have a restful
不同的地方，你会休息
endpoint how do you go get those two
端点你怎么去得到那两个
different things you have to make two
你要做两个不同的事情
API calls right you have to reach back
您必须回溯到API调用权
to the server and say I want all the
到服务器，说我想要所有
user info and now I want all the item
用户信息，现在我想要所有商品
info but you have to make two different
信息，但您必须使两个不同
calls because they're in two different
打电话，因为他们在两个不同的地方
restful endpoints with graph QL you can
可以使用图QL的宁静端点
just make one calling go get everything
只要打个电话就可以得到一切
which is great right so the two specific
很好，所以这两个具体
things that graph QL has in terms of
QL图形在以下方面的功能
advantages over rest are the two things
胜于休息的优势是两件事
I just talked about the first thing is
我刚才说的第一件事是
what we call over fetching I just want
我们所谓的获取只是我想要的
these three fields from the user object
用户对象的这三个字段
and not the other ten fields which are
而不是其他十个领域
there in graph QL you have to be
在图QL中，您必须
explicit and say go get me the user info
明确地说去获取我的用户信息
go get me the user info and just go get
去获取我的用户信息，然后去获取
me these two things
我这两件事
all right so in rest
好吧，休息吧
that problem is known as over fetching
这个问题被称为过度获取
also unrest there's something known as
也动荡不安
under fetching I need something from the
在获取下，我需要从
starships collection and from the
星际飞船系列和
species collection and they're not
物种收集，他们不是
related so in rest I'd have to go make a
相关的，所以在休息时我必须去做一个
call for my starships and a call for my
呼唤我的飞船，呼唤我的飞船
species so I'm making two call instead
种，所以我打了两个电话
of one so graph QL solves that by
因此，图QL通过
allowing you to fetch different
让您获取不同
collections inside the same query ie it
同一查询内的集合即
fixes the under fetching problem okay so
可以解决获取不足的问题
these are the two key advantages of
这些是以下两个主要优点
graph QL over a restful endpoint the
宁静端点上的图QL
other thing is that for those of you who
另一件事是对于那些
raised your hands who are JavaScript
举起你的手谁是JavaScript
front-end people you know that when you
前端人员，您知道，当您
make a network call and you immediately
拨打网络电话，您立即
make a network call your nesting two
让网络呼叫您的嵌套两个
network calls and in grow in JavaScript
网络通话以及JavaScript的增长
that's asynchronous so you have to nest
那是异步的，所以你必须嵌套
them and you start getting into what we
他们，你开始进入我们
call callback hell in asynchronous
异步调用回调地狱
environments and graphic you all you can
尽你所能的环境和图形
avoid that because you just make call
避免那样，因为你只是打电话
and get two different things from two
从两个中得到两个不同的东西
different data sets if you want right
如果需要，可以使用不同的数据集
also just like we're able to go and
就像我们能够去
fetch from two different unconnected
从两个不同的未连接获取
objects we can also go update two
我们也可以去更新两个对象
unconnected objects in the same network
同一网络中的未连接对象
call so it's a variation of the under
打电话，这是下的变化
fetching problem where we can make a
提取问题，我们可以使
graph call query that does a mutation
进行变异的图形调用查询
that's what it's called in graph QL to
这就是在图QL中被称为
go and change an object inside of the
去改变里面的物体
endpoint and say go and change this
端点说去改变这个
object and at the same time change this
对象，并同时更改此
other object okay so grab QL is
其他对象还可以，所以抢QL是
quote-unquote faster and graph QL is
quote-unquote更快，图QL为
quote-unquote simpler now I have that in
报价-取消报价的简单，现在我有
quotes because that's not necessarily
引用，因为这不一定
always the case right there are times
总是有这样的情况
when graph QL is actually slower than
当图QL实际上比
restful endpoint and there are times
宁静的终点，有时
that rust is actually simpler than a
生锈实际上比
graph QL endpoint but in general as
图QL端点，但通常为
you're building out and doing API design
您正在构建并进行API设计
you will find that graph QL on the whole
您会发现整个图的质量QL
is a little bit faster or sometimes much
快一点，有时快很多
faster and also simpler than rest but
比休息更快，也更简单，但是
not always alright so let's talk about
并不总是好的，让我们来谈谈
wildcards a little bit more right
通配符更正确一点
another reason why it's actually nice to
它实际上很好的另一个原因
be explicit about what you specifically
对你具体要明确
are getting from the endpoint is say
从端点得到说
that someone on the team over here
团队中有人在这里
removed a field from the object right
从对象右侧删除字段
you were you weren't expecting it maybe
你当时没想到
you're working on another team or maybe
您正在与另一个团队合作，或者
you're working on the front end right or
您正在前端工作，或者
maybe you're a server-side engineer and
也许您是服务器端工程师，
you want to play a joke on your
你想开个玩笑
front-end engineer or something right so
前端工程师或其他合适的人
if you remove a field what happens in
如果删除字段，将发生什么情况
rest it's just not there anymore all
休息就不再了
right or what happens when you add a
正确，或者添加一个
field on to an object in rest it just
放在静止的物体上
automatically now shows up right so both
现在自动显示正确，因此
of those are problems now if I go back
如果我回去的话，现在有问题了
to my graph QL editor here oh graphical
到我的图形QL编辑器这里哦图形
okay let's say that this field costing
好吧，假设这个领域的成本
credits was removed or let's just make
抵免额已删除，或者我们只赚
up a field let's say that a field called
假设一个字段
home planet was removed from our
原行星从我们的
back-end now when I go run this query
现在后端，当我去运行此查询
you'll see that it gives me some weird
你会发现它给了我一些怪异
air for some reason okay well anyways
反正因为某种原因还可以
the point here is that it actually gives
这里的重点是它实际上给
you an error let's actually try
你是一个错误，让我们实际尝试
something let's get rid of this simplify
让我们摆脱这种简化的东西
this a little bit I'm missing a bracket
这有点我缺少括号
or nine thank you
还是九点谢谢
okay let's try now there we go thank you
好吧，让我们现在尝试那里，我们去谢谢
all right so let's say that we used to
好吧，所以我们说我们曾经
have a field called home planet well I'm
我有一个叫做家星球的领域
look what I'm looking at this in graph
看看我在图上正在看什么
graphical you can see it actually says
图形，你可以看到它实际上说
that but if I actually run it what do we
那但是如果我真的运行它，我们该怎么办
get we actually get an error so if we
得到我们实际上得到一个错误，所以如果我们
have some kind of unit or integration
有某种单位或整合
test how many people don't write tests
测试多少人不写测试
for their software okay there's a couple
他们的软件还可以，有几个
of hands over there I applaud your style
在那边的我赞扬你的风格
I have a t-shirt that says I don't
我有一件T恤说我没有
normally test but when i test i test on
通常测试，但是当我测试时
production so right it's it's a it's a
生产，没错，这是一个，这是一个
big hit at conferences anyways the point
无论如何，在会议上大获成功
here is that because we have a schema
这是因为我们有一个模式
and that schema is rigid in some ways
该模式在某些方面是僵化的
what rigid isn't the right word it's
僵硬的词不是正确的词
very well defined if you remove a field
如果删除字段，定义非常好
you will get an error on the front end
你会在前端得到一个错误
your graph QL query will no longer work
您的图形QL查询将不再起作用
because it'll give you this error your
因为它会给你这个错误
server side will return something and
服务器端将返回一些信息，
say I don't know what feel
说我不知道​​感觉如何
you're talking about okay and the other
你说的还好，另一个
part of this is that when we add a field
这部分是当我们添加一个字段时
we may not want to go get it in our
我们可能不想去得到它
existing queries all right so before I
现有的查询都可以，所以在我之前
showed for example this film connection
例如显示了这个电影连接
here right and this film connection may
在这里，这个电影联系可能
be like a really large object that's
就像一个很大的物体
embedded inside of another object and
嵌入另一个对象的内部
say a server-side engineer adds that new
说服务器端工程师添加了新的
field in that has this massive data
有大量数据的领域
behind it and now all of a sudden in
在它后面，现在突然之间
your restful endpoint you just wanted
您刚刚想要的宁静端点
the user info now you're pulling in the
用户信息，现在您正在
whole item catalog or whatever is a
整个商品目录或任何
related field to it right that's also
与此相关的领域
bad because that causes a big
不好，因为那会导致很大
performance problem or other problems so
性能问题或其他问题
actually being explicit in the fields
实际上在字段中是明确的
that are there and the fields that are
在那里和领域
removed and feels that are added is
删除，感觉是添加的是
actually a good thing because it
实际上是一件好事，因为它
enforces good design it enforces good
实施良好的设计，实施良好的设计
API design okay no a lot of this a lot
API设计好了很多
of stuff that we do in rest is kind of
我们在休息时做的事情是
like magic right we have let's just go
就像魔术一样，我们走吧
get the user info let's go get this and
获取用户信息，让我们开始吧，
that whatever so we one of the things we
那无论如何我们是我们的一件事
avoid with graph with graph QL is we
避免与图QL的图一起使用
avoid that magic it's a little bit more
避免这种魔力
concrete what we're working on so with
具体我们正在做什么
the not having the wild card with the
没有与通配符
app breaks and obvious ways and we don't
应用中断和明显的方式，我们不会
over fetch on new relationships that may
过度获取可能会带来的新关系
be very large and that's very important
非常大，这非常重要
right but you might be thinking oh it's
是的，但您可能会想哦
such a pain for me to have to type out
我必须忍受这种痛苦
every field every time I want to go get
我想去的每个领域都得到
that user info or item object or
该用户信息或项目对象，或
whatever maybe it has 20 or 30 or 50
无论它有20或30或50
fields inside of it and such a pain
里面的田野，如此痛苦
typing them over over and over again
一遍又一遍地打字
well what we can do is we can use
我们可以做的就是可以使用
something called fragments to help
所谓的碎片帮助
alleviate this pain in graph QL all
缓解图QL中的所有疼痛
right what does the fragment look like
片段看起来像什么
say we have something like users so we
说我们有类似用户的东西，所以我们
would create a fragment call user
将创建一个片段呼叫用户
fragment that would contain some basic
包含一些基本内容的片段
field data that we want to get maybe
我们想要获取的现场数据
every time we use it so you can see I
每次我们使用它，以便您可以看到我
have a fragment called user fragment
有一个片段叫做用户片段
here and then when I want to go use that
在这里，然后当我想去使用
user fragment you can see on the bottom
您可以在底部看到的用户片段
I say fetch users user with I it to and
我说用它来获取用户用户并
then I do dot dot dot user fragment so
然后我做点点用户片段
that uses that user fragment then you
使用该用户片段，然后您
can reuse that fragment in the different
可以在不同的地方重用该片段
places where you need to go get the same
你需要去的地方也一样
set of fields every time so you don't
每次都使用一组字段，这样您就不会
have to type them out over
必须把它们打出来
and over again okay all right and we'll
再说一遍好吧，我们会
get into this a bit later but how do we
稍后再讨论这个，但是我们该如何
actually go and change data so far we've
到目前为止，我们实际上一直在更改数据
only gone into a two-week query data out
只花了两周的查询数据
of graph QL and this is what you do for
QL图，这就是您要做的
mutation we'll look at that in just a
突变，我们将在一个
minute
分钟
okay actually we're gonna jump to our
好吧，实际上我们要跳到我们的
code here and talk about graph QL and
在这里编码并讨论图QL和
Java so there are two main libraries for
Java，因此有两个主要的库
doing stuff there's one called graph QL
做的事情有一个叫做图QL
Java which is a very low-level library
Java是一个非常低级的库
for building graph cool stuff I will
用于构建图很酷的东西
have a look at that in a second and
一秒钟看看
there's another one called graph QL SPQR
还有一个叫做图QL SPQR的图
or pronounced speaker which is a
或发音明显的说话者
graphical library which is a little bit
图形库有点
more sophisticated for building out a
建立一个更复杂的
graph QL server and I like diagrams so I
图QL服务器，我喜欢图，所以我
put this one together that shows you how
放在一起，向您展示如何
you do a diagram or how you do graph
你做图或做图
kill or where it says so you stub your
杀死它或说出来的地方，这样就存根
database or it could be anything else
数据库或其他任何东西
you can still use JDBC and JPA and then
您仍然可以使用JDBC和JPA，然后
you have graph queue on top of it which
你有图队列在上面
makes your endpoint which is what your
使您的端点是您的
client would actually then use okay and
客户实际上会使用ok和
the data could be anything right so
数据可能是正确的，所以
we're gonna use it are just a h2 in
我们将使用它只是一个H2
memory our DBMS for this demo but it can
为该演示存储我们的DBMS，但可以
be anything you can expose something off
做任何你可以暴露的东西
the file system if you wanted or if you
文件系统（如果需要）还是
have some kind of network server if you
有某种网络服务器，如果您
have a Redis server that has like
有一个Redis服务器
transitory information like just stored
暂时性信息，如刚刚存储的
in memory you can expose that through
在内存中，您可以通过
graph cool you can expose anything you
图很酷，您可以暴露任何东西
want it's not necessarily just a
希望它不一定只是一个
database behind it okay so when we're
后面的数据库还可以，所以当我们
defining an API and we can wrap anything
定义一个API，我们可以包装任何东西
you want okay that's one of the great
你想好吧，那是伟大的之一
things about graph queue on again let's
关于图队列的事情再次让我们
jump into our demo
进入我们的演示
what about 21 minutes so I'm gonna speed
大约21分钟怎么办，我要加快速度
things up a little bit and this is our
事情有点，这是我们的
first demo here okay so in this one I'm
第一次演示在这里，所以在这个
just using the standard graph QL Java
只是使用标准图QL Java
API so we need to have a couple
API，所以我们需要几个
different things but let's start with
不同的事情，但让我们开始
our domain objects so you can see I have
我们的域对象，以便您可以看到我有
my ant ant identity so this is just
我的蚂蚁身份，这就是
standard JPA and here is my annotations
标准的JPA，这是我的注释
for all those different things all right
对于所有这些不同的事情都可以
standard entity object book and author
标准实体对象书和作者
okay so we have two different
好，所以我们有两个不同
annotations or entities here okay just
注释或实体在这里可以
make sure right and every book has an
确保正确，每本书都有
author so we say here's our author
作者，所以我们说这是我们的作者
relationship
关系
from book and these are just standard
从书中，这些只是标准
repositories so you can probably guess
仓库，所以您可能会猜到
what this is if I open this up this is
如果我打开这个，这是什么
just a crud repository and again just a
只是一个原始库，再一次
card repository is everyone from
卡存储库来自每个人
familiar with spring data repositories
熟悉Spring数据存储库
like jpn credit repositories yeah okay
就像JPN信用库一样，是的
most I mean is this a spring conference
我最主要的意思是这是春季会议
okay just making sure
好，只要确保
so you probably know what this is so I
所以你可能知道这是什么
won't spend any time on that right what
不会花任何时间在正确的地方
I want to spend time on is let's have a
我想花时间去让我们
look at the actual application so what
看一下实际的应用
we have is this is an air handler we'll
我们有这是一个空气处理器
look at this air handler in just a
看看这个空气处理器
second but you can see if we go up here
第二，但是你可以看看我们是否在这里
this is a standard spring boot
这是标准的 spring boot
application right here okay and now I
应用程序就可以了，现在我
have a couple beans defined here book
在这里定义了几个豆书
resolver the query resolver a mutation
解析器查询解析器的一个突变
resolver and this is just a command line
解析器，这只是一个命令行
runner for doing some testing but let's
亚军进行一些测试，但让我们
go actually have a look at those and
去看看这些
again those are just beans they get
同样，这些只是他们得到的豆子
injected into our graph QL server so
注入到我们的图QL服务器中
let's start with query and we take the
让我们从查询开始，我们将
repositories like so and we have find
这样的存储库，我们发现
all books and find all authors and that
所有书籍，找到所有作者，
goes in queries the repositories and we
去查询存储库，我们
have count book and count authors okay
有书本和作者数没关系
so our query basically implements this
所以我们的查询基本上实现了这个
graph QL graph QL query resolve our
图QL图QL查询解决我们
objects so this is when you're using
对象，所以这是当您使用
this specific library this is the entry
这个特定的库，这是条目
point for our graph QL server so we
点为我们的图QL服务器，所以我们
basically create this query object that
基本上创建这个查询对象
implements graph QL runner or sorry
实现图QL赛跑者或遗憾
graph QL resolver and we go and define
图QL解析器，我们去定义
these specific operations to go and look
这些具体的操作要去看看
at this so let's go start this up from
在这一点上，让我们开始
the command line make sure this works I
命令行确保它可以正常工作
think I already have it running okay
认为我已经可以运行了
great
大
so let's go into here and let's just run
所以我们进入这里，让我们开始吧
count books really quickly right so you
很快就可以数书了，所以你
can see we have one book in here right
可以看到我们这里有一本书
now I'm just gonna comment this out and
现在我要评论一下
now I'm gonna run find all books like so
现在我要去寻找所有像这样的书
let's go run that and you can see I
让我们运行它，你可以看到我
currently have one book in our database
目前在我们的数据库中有一本书
and if we remember find all books and
如果我们还记得找到所有的书和
count books and go into our query class
数书籍并进入我们的查询类
which implements graphical query
实现图形查询
resolver you can see I've find all books
解析器，您可以看到我已找到所有书籍
find all authors count books count
查找所有作者数书数
authors so if I change that if I were to
作者，所以如果我更改，如果我要
change this from find all books to find
从查找所有书籍更改为查找
authors it would return that okay but
作者，它将返回还可以，但
let's go look at the resolve
让我们来看一下解决方法
really quickly and what the resolver
真的很快，什么是解析器
looks like so iBook resolver implements
看起来像是iBook解析器实现
graph QL resolver and you can see
图QL解析器，您可以看到
underneath the hood it basically goes
在引擎盖下面
and gets the authors repository and the
并获取作者存储库和
reason why we need this resolver is
我们需要此解析器的原因是
because our our book has a relationship
因为我们的书有关系
to another object we wish to expose
到我们希望暴露的另一个对象
through graph QL called author so we
通过图QL称为作者，所以我们
have to set up this resolver so from
必须设置此解析器
within our query or find all books it
在我们的查询中或查找所有书籍
can go and figure out where that
可以去找出那个地方
underlying contained object is right and
底层包含的对象是正确的，
if we wanted to save a author we would
如果我们想保存一个作者，我们会
create a mutation which implements graph
创建一个实现图的变异
QL mutation resolver and then it goes
QL突变解析器，然后运行
exposes something called a new book so
揭露一本叫做新书的东西
if I again if I come into here and let
如果我再次来到这里，让我
me just comment this out for now write
我只是将其注释掉，现在写
comment it out and if I were to come
评论一下，如果我要来
here and say what was it called again in
在这里说一遍又叫什么
your book right so I'm gonna be lazy and
你的书没错，所以我会很懒
just say u that's not right what did
只是说你那是不对的
that happen oh I think my command key
发生这种情况哦，我想我的命令键
got stuck okay I'm gonna skip that demo
卡住了，好，我要跳过该演示
for now but anyways this is how we do it
现在，但是无论如何，这就是我们要做的
now I don't want to spend too much time
现在我不想花太多时间
on this because well this is good for
在此上，因为这对
building like a low-level API
像底层API一样进行构建
unfortunately there's a lot of work that
不幸的是，有很多工作
needs to be done all right one of the
需要做的所有事情之一
reasons we use spring and things like
我们使用弹簧的原因以及诸如此类的东西
micro profile with annotations and c-d-i
带有注释和CDI的微资料
and all those things is because we don't
而所有这些事情是因为我们不
want to write all this code we want to
想写所有我们想要的代码
spend as little time writing as code as
花费与编写代码一样少的时间
as possible how many people like to
尽可能多的人喜欢
write lots of code by the way anybody
用任何人的方式写很多代码
know why don't we like to write a lot of
知道为什么我们不喜欢写很多
code because the more code you'd write
代码，因为您要编写的代码更多
the more code you have to test and the
您必须测试的代码越多，
more code can potentially have bugs and
更多代码可能存在错误，并且
break down right so that's why we like
正确分解，这就是为什么我们喜欢
to use spring because we can write less
使用spring，因为我们可以减少写
code so the library I prefer to do it
代码，所以我更喜欢这样做的库
you do this is called graph QL speaker
您执行此操作称为图QL扬声器
which uses annotations so that we have
它使用注释，以便我们拥有
to write less of this kind of
少写这种
boilerplate and have less ceremony to do
样板和更少的仪式要做
this kind of stuff so let's have a quick
这种东西，让我们快速
look at another sample project that uses
看看另一个使用的示例项目
this other library okay so let's start
另一个图书馆好吧，让我们开始
with our basic object and in this case
与我们的基本目标，在这种情况下
because I really don't want to write
因为我真的不想写
code in this project I'm using what's
这个项目中的代码我正在使用什么
called Project Lombok which you can see
叫做Project Lombok，您可以看到
is imported here but it gives me
在这里进口但是它给了我
annotations like this so I don't have to
这样的注释，所以我不必
write all the getters and setters and
写所有的getter和setter
all that stuff how many people use
所有这些东西，多少人使用
Project Lombok in here just how to carry
龙目岛项目在这里如何携带
out okay good that's I think everybody's
好的，那是我想每个人的
hand went up so I won't explain that
手上升了，所以我不会解释
part all right but you can see I have my
好的，但是你可以看到我有我的
entity object here and then I say Oh at
实体对象在这里，然后我在
graph QL query name is ID description
图QL查询名称是ID描述
blah blah blah private long ID graph
等等等等私人长ID图
cool query name blah blah blah so
很酷的查询名称等等等等等等
instead of having to write those
不必写那些
resolvers and other things like that I
解析器和其他类似的东西
basically just put an annotation on a
基本上只是在
field and say this field is now
领域，说这个领域现在
queryable right this is great so let's
可查询的权利，这很好，让我们
work I have to do so now we look at our
我现在必须要做的工作
car service nothing fancy in here but I
汽车服务在这里没什么花哨的，但我
have get car by ID and this is where so
已经通过身份证获得汽车，这就是那里
in here I say go and allow this thing to
在这里我说去，允许这件事
be queryable and now if I go into my car
可以查询，现在如果我上车
service which has my cars like so
我的车像这样的服务
alright I can say get car by ID name ID
好吧，我可以说按ID名称ID取车
etc going fine from the repository
等从存储库中顺利进行
object that car and also you can see
反对那辆车，你也可以看到
it's annotated with a craft QL query for
它带有工艺QL查询的注释
car so this is our route entry point
汽车，所以这是我们的路线入口点
into the car object but I've also
进入汽车对象，但我也
defined a mutation called add graph QL
定义了一个称为添加图QL的突变
mutation the name of that mutation is
突变的名称是
car safe car right so it can be
汽车 Vault 正确，所以它可以
different than the actual name of the
与实际名称不同
method if I want and it takes in a type
我想要的方法，它接受一个类型
of this specific car and you can see
这辆特定的汽车，您可以看到
there's some extra annotations in here
这里有一些额外的注释
and I call the underlying graph QL
我称基础图为QL
repository let's go run this make sure
仓库让我们去运行这个确保
it works real quick ok let's quit out of
它真的很有效，好的，让我们退出
here and do a spring boot run on this
在这里做一个 spring boot
real quick see if this is working ok ok
真正的快速看看这是否正常
come on setting up the database and
来建立数据库，
everything so it might take a second and
一切，所以可能需要一秒钟，
you can see I'm just injecting in some
你可以看到我只是在注入一些
initial values for us to play around
我们可以玩的初始值
with ok so let's go again to our
好的，让我们再回到我们的
graphical just do a reload and oops I
图形只是做一个重载，哎呀我
think I ran that mutation I didn't mean
以为我跑了那个我不是故意的突变
to do that
要做到这一点
ok so let's go look at our cars and
好吧，让我们去看看我们的车，
let's make sure this works oh wow thank
让我们确保这有效哦谢谢
god it worked
天哪
ok
好
but if you remember in from this output
但是如果您记得从此输出中
right here
就在这儿
I just just for testing I inserted this
我只是为了测试我插入了这个
into the memory database for our a
进入我们的内存数据库
Jaguar Porsche blah blah blah blah blah
捷豹保时捷等等等等等等等等
so it looks like I have nine things so I
所以看起来我有九件事，所以我
should have nine cars here and now if we
如果我们现在应该在这里有九辆车
go back to our code really quickly we
很快地回到我们的代码，我们
were calling the car right so this is
打电话给汽车，所以这是
the name that I actually referenced
我实际引用的名称
right here four cars right I'm sorry I
在这里四辆车对不起我
was getting a list of cars so graph QL
正在获取汽车列表，所以图QL
query name equals cars is basically
查询名称基本等于汽车
running this line of code in our server
在我们的服务器上运行这一行代码
okay
好的
now the great thing about this is that
现在关于这个的伟大的事情是
we just go and annotate things and say
我们只是去注释事物并说
this is the entry point for my cars
这是我的车的入口
object what gives me a list of cars and
反对什么给了我汽车清单
this is my car over here by car object
这是我在这里乘车的车
forgetting a specific car and because we
忘记了一辆特定的汽车，因为我们
have strong typing in Java and all the
在Java中具有强大的输入能力，
stuff is there we basically are graph QL
东西在那里，我们基本上是图QL
schema is auto-generated for us by just
模式是为我们自动生成的
inserting these annotations into the
将这些注释插入
appropriate places which is really nice
合适的地方，真的很好
that means it's less work for us to do
这意味着我们要做的工作更少
and again we get this nice API browser
再一次，我们得到了这个不错的API浏览器
called graphic graphical and we can go
称为图形图形，我们可以去
browse the docs here so we can say let's
在这里浏览文档，所以我们可以说
go look at the entry point for query and
去看看查询的入口点，
here's cars and it contains a type of
这是汽车，其中包含一种
car and that car has a giffy URL ID is
汽车，而该汽车的网址URL ID是
cool and name so if i go back to my code
很酷的名字，所以如果我回到我的代码
you can see that we have some additional
您可以看到我们还有一些其他功能
stuff well that's interesting where is
有趣的东西在哪里
this where is this gift fee URL coming
这个礼品费网址在哪里
from hmm okay so it's not in my car
从嗯好吧，所以不在我的车里
object so where is that it is where's
对象，所以它在哪里
that gift fee URL if you remember what I
礼物费网址，如果您还记得我
said earlier graph QL is just a
说之前的图QL只是一个
specification for building out an API
建立API的规范
and we have to build out that API as
我们必须将API建立为
developers so in this case what I'm
开发人员，在这种情况下，我是
doing is I'm using my car entity object
我正在使用我的汽车实体对象
as the base a let's say the base object
作为基础，假设基础对象
and then I could just add in some random
然后我可以随机添加一些
crap to it if I want okay so let's go
如果我想好吧就废话吧，走吧
search in this code base for Q
在此代码库中搜索Q
to URL where is that thing oops
到URL，这是怎么回事
hope so I can type giffy URL okay
希望我可以输入giffy URL好的
there's something called giffy service
有一种叫做吉菲的服务
here so that's this string okay okay
这是这个字符串，好吧，好吧
let's go here and now again I'm in my
让我们去这里，现在我又在
car service alright so if i zoom in here
好的汽车服务，所以如果我在这里放大
you can see I'm in car service and now
你可以看到我现在在开车
if I scroll down a little bit you can
如果我向下滚动一点，您可以
see I have this thing called give free
看到我有这个东西叫给免费
URL alright so what I'm actually doing
网址不错，所以我实际上在做什么
is I'm saying that in the context of
我是说在上下文中
this car object go and add an extra
这个汽车对象去添加一个额外的
field which is not part of that actual
不属于该实际部分的字段
entity which we're basically just adding
我们基本上只是添加的实体
it like dynamically if you will as part
如果您愿意的话，它就像动态地一样
of the query mechanism in graph QL
QL中查询机制的说明
so we're saying go get the give you RL
所以我们说去得到给你的RL
right and what this is doing that
对，这在做什么
underneath the hood it's is using this
引擎盖下面是使用这个
giffy service which goes and makes a
轻薄的服务，使
call to giffy and gets us back the
打电话给吉菲，让我们回到
actual URL I don't need to show that
实际的网址，我不需要显示
part but the point here is that again
部分，但重点是
it's we don't just wrap a sinto simple
这是我们不只是简单地包装一个罪过
entity object or just a java class or
实体对象或只是Java类或
something what we can do is we can
我们可以做的是
actually just add something or anything
实际上只是添加一些东西
in this case I go and make a call to the
在这种情况下，我去打电话给
giffy service which is here and I go and
礼貌的服务在这里，我去，
attach that data to that actual object
将该数据附加到该实际对象
at runtime in this car service ok so
在这个汽车服务的运行时间还可以
it's just a demo of like it's it can be
只是一个演示而已
very flexible and you can do all sorts
非常灵活，您可以进行各种操作
of crazy or useful things even to go and
疯狂甚至有用的东西
build out this API so let's go back to
建立这个API，让我们回到
our API browser here so you can see that
我们的API浏览器在这里，您可以看到
we have these gifty URLs and everything
我们有这些精美的网址以及所有内容
ok now let's say we want to add a car
好的，现在我们要添加一辆车
all right so let's go I'm just gonna
好吧，让我们走吧，我要
comment this out for now all right so
现在就注释掉这个吧
let's go and add something okay I'm
我们去加点好吧，我是
gonna say mutation save car Tesla Model
要说变异保存汽车特斯拉模型
S extreme well the Tesla 3 just came out
特斯拉3刚刚问世
we'll add that in a minute
一会儿我们将其添加
ID name etc ok so ID will get Auto
ID名称等确定，因此ID将自动
generated we have to provide a name
生成的我们必须提供一个名称
which we do right here so here's car :
我们在这里做的就是车：
name :
名称 ：
now let's go look at this specific thing
现在让我们来看一下这件事
let's go find the save car in here ok
我们去这里找救车好吧
let's do F save car oh here it is save
让我们去保存汽车哦，这是保存
car and you can see it takes a car type
汽车，你会看到它需要一辆汽车
but it expects it to be wrapped inside
但它希望将其包裹在里面
of some kind of car
某种汽车
container thingamajig and we passed that
容器thingamajig，我们通过了
down into here all right so let's go run
进入这里好吧，让我们开始吧
that really quickly okay so we got the
真的很快就可以了，所以我们得到了
data back and now if right and again a
数据返回，如果正确又一次
mutation is how we make a change or
突变是我们做出改变的方式，或者
essentially do something like an update
本质上是做更新
or whatever if you want think in terms
或者如果您想用术语思考
of sequel right now you can see this is
现在你可以看到这是续集
taking a second the reason why I took a
我花了第二个理由
minute is because I don't have all the
分钟是因为我没有所有
data there that I need for this pacific
太平洋所需的数据
call right
通话权
what's the bit of data that I don't have
我没有什么数据
contained in the entity object the gippy
包含在实体对象中的吉普赛人
URL exactly so that's why I took a
网址正是这样，这就是为什么我选择了
second because the server actually
第二，因为服务器实际上
reached out thankfully the Internet is
值得庆幸的是，互联网是
working on my laptop right so when it
在我的笔记本电脑上工作就可以了
was going and inserting that and we were
在去插入那个，我们在
going in getting this data it actually
实际获取这些数据
going had to had to go and call this
不得不不得不去叫这个
giffy service which goes and makes and
去做的软弱的服务和
you can see this is building an HTTP
您可以看到这正在构建一个HTTP
client it actually reached out to give
它实际上伸出手给的客户
he got that data back and attached it to
他将数据取回并附加到
that specific object okay so that's how
该特定对象还可以，所以
we did that specific thing meant let's
我们做了那个特定的事情意味着让我们
just double check did we get a giffy for
只是仔细检查，我们是否对
this yeah I'm just interested to see
是的，我只是想看看
what kind of gift he had pull back for a
他拉回什么样的礼物
Tesla what okay whatever
特斯拉好吗
it's maybe that bit of code needs some
也许这部分代码需要一些
work but anyways you get the idea right
工作，但无论如何您都会得到正确的想法
so similarly we have something else here
同样，我们在这里还有其他东西
another kind of static well doesn't go
另一种静态井不会消失
out to the internet called is cool so
上网很酷，所以
again if we flip back to our browser you
再次，如果我们回到浏览器，您
can see that all these cars are cool or
可以看到所有这些车都很棒
not cool or some of them are cool but we
不酷或其中一些很酷，但我们
go and essentially just have like a
去，基本上就像
static set or whatever okay but anyways
静态设置还是可以的，但是无论如何
the point here is that the way that we
这里的重点是我们的方式
can build out an API is very flexible
可以建立一个API非常灵活
and because we have this nice library
而且因为我们有这个漂亮的图书馆
like graph QL speaker we can build out
像图QL扬声器一样，我们可以建立
out very quickly without having to go
不用走很快就能出去
and add a lot of boilerplate and have
并添加很多样板并具有
extra classes we can just use the
我们可以使用额外的类
annotations to build everything and if
注释来构建一切，如果
we're interested to see how all this
我们有兴趣看看这一切
comes together let's just have a quick
在一起，让我们快速
look at the well let's start at the top
看一下井，让我们从顶部开始
here's our graph cool web configure all
这是我们的图酷网站配置所有
right so if we go look at this what
对，所以如果我们去看看这个
we're doing is we're using the spring
我们正在做的是我们正在使用弹簧
web NBC configure right here right we
Web NBC在这里配置我们
say this is we're gonna add this extra
说这是我们要添加的额外费用
view for graphic graphical so the
查看图形图形
graphical like UI that I've been using
我一直在使用的图形用户界面
just to demo this it's just a jar file
只是为了演示这只是一个jar文件
if you drop that jar file into a graph
如果您将该jar文件放入图表中
QL server application we can very easily
QL服务器应用程序我们可以很轻松地
expose it like so so that we have this
这样暴露它，以便我们拥有这个
testing endpoint as well and of course
当然也要测试端点
we have to have an index dot HTML which
我们必须有一个索引点HTML
is the front-end code or whatever but we
是前端代码或其他什么，但我们
can have this at this specific location
可以在这个特定的位置
all right so if i zoom in here you can
好吧，如果我在这里放大，你可以
see that I'm going to I'm going to slash
看到我要去斜线
graph QL and that's how we set that part
图形QL，这就是我们设置该部分的方式
up over here okay and again you just
在这里好，再一次，你只是
have to drop a jar file if we go into
我们必须放入一个jar文件
our palm down XML and we scroll up it'll
我们将XML下移，然后向上滚动
be here somewhere
在某处
I hope hope it's here somewhere all
我希望它在这里
right so actually it's embedded inside
对，所以实际上它嵌入了里面
of this graph QL speaker library but
图QL扬声器库
it's very easy to set that up and let's
设置起来很容易，让我们
finally just have a quick look at the
最后，快速浏览一下
graphical controller so what we do is we
图形控制器，所以我们要做的是
say initialize a new graphical schema
说初始化一个新的图形模式
generator and again that class is from
生成器，并且该类再次来自
our graph QL speaker library right right
我们的图QL扬声器库右右
here and we'll say use these resolvers
在这里，我们会说使用这些解析器
build a new annotation resolver it'll go
建立一个新的注释解析器
and scan the class path find those
并扫描课程路径，找到那些
annotations use operations from this
注释使用此操作
service right so you saw the car service
服务正确，所以您看到了汽车服务
before create a value map or factory
在创建价值图或工厂之前
this is just for the Jackson so that
这只是为了杰克逊
creates our schema these lines of code
创建这些代码行的架构
and go and create our graph QL schema
然后创建我们的图QL模式
dynamically ok so we don't even have to
动态地确定，所以我们甚至不必
go and like do any hard coding or
去做任何硬编码或
whatever
随你
now I didn't show this earlier but I do
现在我没有显示这个，但是我做了
want to mention it quickly you don't
想快速提起您不
have to build everything out in code
必须用代码构建一切
like this what you can actually do is
这样，您实际上可以做的是
this is from the previous example using
这是从上一个示例中使用的
the low-level graph QL Java library all
低级图QL Java库全部
right we can actually go and write out
对，我们实际上可以去写出来
the actual schema using the graph QL
使用图QL的实际模式
schema format which is this stuff right
模式格式，这是正确的东西
here right or if you're lazy like me you
在这里或者如果您像我一样懒
just say you know what I'm just going to
只是说你知道我要去
I'm just gonna go and annotate all my
我要去注释我所有的东西
stuff like so and you go and build a
这样的东西，你去建立一个
schema for me because I don't want to do
为我设计模式，因为我不想做
that ok so anyways we build out the
好的，无论如何，我们建立了
schema we create a new graph QL from
模式，我们从中创建一个新的图QL
that schema
该模式
here's our post mapping for the slash
这是我们的斜线发布映射
craft QL endpoint and the rest of it is
工艺QL端点，其余的是
relatively straightforward we say from
我们说相对简单
the graph QL schema go and execute that
图QL模式去执行
new query based on the input that was
基于输入的新查询
provided okay and that's how we build
提供好的，这就是我们的方式
out a graph QL server in Java using this
在Java中使用此图QL服务器
specific library alright so let's just
好的特定库，所以让我们
make sure we've covered everything here
确保我们已经涵盖了这里的所有内容
I think we have I'm gonna just skip over
我想我们要跳过
these slides I only have a couple
这些幻灯片，我只有一对
minutes but with this using either graph
分钟，但使用任一图表
QL the graph QL Java library or the
QL图形QL Java库或
graphical speaker you can build out a
图形扬声器，您可以建立一个
graph QL server like we did here using
像我们在这里使用图QL服务器
spring boot or if you use micro profile
spring boot 或如果您使用微型轮廓
you can use micro profile or whatever
您可以使用微资料或其他任何内容
right and actually you may have noticed
对，实际上您可能已经注意到
earlier that inside one of these
早在其中之一
applications which one was it right if
如果哪一个是正确的应用
you want to also build out something
你也想建立一些东西
that just runs from the command line you
只是从命令行运行
can see it you has anybody written a
可以看到你有任何人写过
spring command line app before anybody a
Spring命令行应用程序在任何人之前
few people yeah so this is just a
很少有人，这只是一个
standard spring command line runner
标准弹簧命令行运行器
objects so you can actually write a
对象，因此您实际上可以编写一个
graph QL like program I'm not a server
图QL像程序我不是服务器
in this case by just going again and
在这种情况下，只需再次
using this library okay so let's go back
好的使用这个库，让我们回去
to here get back to our slides okay so
回到这里，回到幻灯片吧
we've covered pretty much everything you
我们已经涵盖了您几乎所有的一切
need to know but there are a couple of
需要知道，但有几个
things that we haven't covered for
我们没有涵盖的事情
example authentication and authorization
认证和授权示例
how do you do that against graph QL
您如何针对图QL做到这一点
there's unfortunately we don't have time
不幸的是我们没有时间
to get into all that but you can find
进入所有的东西，但你可以找到
some examples out there which walk you
一些例子，带你走
through setting up authentication and
通过设置身份验证和
authorization it's not very difficult
授权不是很难
it's what you would expect we also
这就是您期望的，我们也
didn't get too much detail into features
没有太多的功能细节
like pagination right I showed how you
就像分页一样，我向你展示了
can just get the first one or the first
可以得到第一个或第一个
two or last one last two in an earlier
早些时候的两个或倒数第二个
demonstration but the thing to note is
示范，但要注意的是
for example when you want to do
例如当你想做的时候
pagination when we're building out a
分页时，我们正在建立一个
graph QL server we have to write
图QL服务器我们必须编写
everything you saw me add annotations to
您看到的所有内容都会添加注释
the car service and to the car object so
汽车服务以及对汽车的对象
when we're doing that we're basically
当我们这样做时，我们基本上是
building out a graph QL
建立图QL
server so if you want to do pagination
服务器，所以如果你想做分页
you have to have the ability inside of
你必须具备内在的能力
your entity object or your service
您的实体对象或服务
object to go and get paginate of data
反对去获取数据分页
right so it doesn't come for free that
对，所以它不是免费的
server-side stuff doesn't come for free
服务器端的东西不是免费的
you have to still have the ability to do
你仍然有能力去做
pagination and then graph QL allows you
分页，然后用图QL允许您
to expose that pagination into the graph
将分页显示在图中
QL library okay so we didn't cover
QL库好，所以我们没有涵盖
pagination in our code examples here we
在我们的代码示例中进行分页
talked a little bit about mutations and
谈到了一些突变，
changes in updates but we didn't get
更新中的变化，但我们没有得到
into too much detail on that either
在这方面有太多细节
unfortunately so I'm gonna stop there
不幸的是，我要停在那里
because I have about 20 seconds left
因为我还剩20秒左右
where how much time do I have left
我还剩下多少时间
am I done no more time I'll keep going
我是否再没有时间继续前进了
okay
好的
[Music]
[音乐]